<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MacOS on SPERIXLABS</title>
    <link>https://sperixlabs.org/tags/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MacOS on SPERIXLABS</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>SPERIXLABS</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:19:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sperixlabs.org/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Vault: A Deep Dive into macOS ARM64 Trial Enforcement and Binary Patching</title>
      <link>https://sperixlabs.org/post/2026/02/unlocking-the-vault-a-deep-dive-into-macos-arm64-trial-enforcement-and-binary-patching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 10:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sperixlabs.org/post/2026/02/unlocking-the-vault-a-deep-dive-into-macos-arm64-trial-enforcement-and-binary-patching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the course of analyzing a decompiled macOS productivity application—a calendar and meeting alert utility with a time-limited trial—we encountered a multi-layered enforcement mechanism governing trial expiry, feature gating, and application termination. This practice is common in commercial software: when the trial expires, the app displays warnings, disables premium features, and eventually terminates unless the user purchases or restores a license.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article documents the complete reverse engineering journey: from initial string reconnaissance through call-graph tracing, assembly-level analysis, and ultimately the development of six binary patches that bypass trial termination, re-enable gated features, and customize the UI—all without modifying the application&amp;rsquo;s source code or runtime environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Sign macOS PKG Files for Deployment</title>
      <link>https://sperixlabs.org/post/2022/02/how-to-sign-macos-pkg-files-for-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 09:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sperixlabs.org/post/2022/02/how-to-sign-macos-pkg-files-for-deployment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Signing a package is a multi-step process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generate a signing request.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generate Developer ID Installer certificate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sign the macOS PKG file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;steps-to-generate-a-signing-request&#34;&gt;Steps to Generate a Signing Request&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For generating a certificate, first of all you require a Certificate Signing Request (CSR) file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open “&lt;strong&gt;Keychain Access&lt;/strong&gt;” program within your macOS device.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Click on Keychain Access appearing on the top menu bar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;strong&gt;Certificate Assistant&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Request a Certificate From a Certificate Authority&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your email address in the User Email Address field, and name in the Common Name field. Leave the CA Email Address field blank.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Under the Request is option, click Saved to Disc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Click Continue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Specify the location on the device where the .csr file is to be saved and click Save.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The signing request will be saved to your machine in the specified location. This file is required to generate the “&lt;strong&gt;Developer ID Installer&lt;/strong&gt;” certificate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
